<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[BeScala]]></title>
  <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-10T00:11:36+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[BeScala]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup October 10th - Molecule: Using Monadic and Streaming I/O to Compose Process Networks on the JVM]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/meetup-october-10th/"/>
    <updated>2012-10-01T21:36:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/meetup-october-10th</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Writing and maintaining concurrent applications that exploit parallelism in multicore environment is a challenging task on the JVM. In absence of coroutines, programming against non-blocking I/O interfaces forces developers to give up traditional control structures offered transparently by native threads such as termination management and exception handling. Managing these explicitly in a program often turns out into a maintenance nightmare for any non-trivial application. Moreover, in absence of good scheduling strategies, the performance of concurrent applications that exhibit a high amount of context switches may degrade significantly when they are scheduled over more than one thread.</p>

<p>In this talk, we present Molecule, a domain specific language in Scala and a runtime library for developing concurrent applications on the JVM. Molecule applications are designed as process networks that communicate over strongly typed channel interfaces. Molecule abstracts user-level threads that interact over non-blocking interfaces behind a monad that takes care of automatic resource management and exception handling. Its strongly typed channel interfaces can be manipulated as lazy streams in functional programming languages, which contribute to increase the overall expressiveness of lightweight processes. Its runtime implement a flow parallel scheduler that eliminates thread context switches when processes communicate sequentially. We will illustrate its expressiveness and performance benefits over several examples during the talk.</p>

<p>This BeScala meetup is proposed and hosted by <a href="http://www.alcatel-lucent.com/be">Alcatel-Lucent</a> in Antwerp.
Our host, Sébastien Bocq, will also be presenting this framework at the <a href="http://splashcon.org/2012/program/oopsla-research-papers/466-concurrency-ii">OOPSLA conference</a></p>

<p>For organisation reasons, you <strong>must</strong> <a href="http://bescala.fikket.com/event/molecule">register</a> on the Fikket page and registrations will end Tuesday October 9th at 17h00.
Also on the day of the event registration at the Alcatel-Lucent front desk must happen before 19h00.</p>

<p>Direction:
Copernicuslaan 50
2018 Antwerpen
Belgium</p>

<p><a href="http://www.alcatel-lucent.com/be">http://www.alcatel-lucent.com/be</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup Oct 24th - AROM: a distributed parallel processing framework]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/arom/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-11T23:44:01+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/arom</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The development in computational processing has driven towards distributed processing frameworks performing tasks in parallel setups. The recent advances in Cloud Computing have widely contributed to this tendency. The MapReduce model proposed by Google is one of the most popular despite the well-known limitations inherent to the model which constrain the types of jobs that can be expressed. On the other hand models based on Data Flow Graphs (DFG) for the processing and the definition of the jobs, while more complex to express, are more general and suitable for a wider range of tasks, including iterative and pipelined tasks.</p>

<p>In this talk we present AROM, a framework for large scale distributed processing based on DFG to express the jobs and which uses paradigms from functional programming to define the operators. The former leads to more natural handling of pipelined tasks while the latter enhances genericity and reusability of the operators.</p>

<p><a href="https://github.com/nltran/arom"> </a>This BeScala meetup is proposed and hosted by <strong><a href="http://euranova.eu/">Eura Nova</a></strong> in Louvain-la-Neuve (Mont-Saint-Guibert).</p>

<p>Please <strong><a href="http://bescala.fikket.com/events/arom-a-distributed-parallel-processing-framework/orders/new">register</a></strong> on the fikket page, as we have to limit participation.</p>

<p><strong>Direction</strong>:
Rue Émile Francqui, 4
1435 Mont-Saint-Guibert</p>

<p><a href="http://euranova.eu/">http://euranova.eu/</a></p>

<p><a href="http://arom-processing.org/">http://arom-processing.org/</a></p>

<p>The AROM framework source code is available at <a href="https://github.com/nltran/arom">https://github.com/nltran/arom</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BeScala @ Devoxx 2012]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-devoxx-2012/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-04T01:14:24+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-devoxx-2012</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that our rendez-vous at <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/">Devoxx 2012</a> is confirmed.</p>

<p>Come and join us on Monday 12th November at 19:00 on the <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV12/Scala+Enthusiasts+Gathering">Scala Enthusiasts Gathering BoF</a> for a informal meet-up with other Scala enthusiasts from Belgium and abroad.</p>

<p>The access to the BoFs are <strong>free of charge</strong>, but of course we <strong>strongly</strong> <strong>recommend</strong> a Devoxx subscription. As usual, Devoxx is featuring a lot of excellent <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV12/Schedule">talks</a>, some of them on <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/label/DV12/scala">Scala</a>.</p>

<p>Don&#8217;t wait till the last minute, get today your Devoxx <a href="https://reg.devoxx.com/public/#DV12">subscription</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://reg.devoxx.com/public/#DV12"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/devoxx-2012-horiz.gif" alt="Devoxx 2012" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Meetup Sept 27th - Some Monads after the holidays]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/some-monads-after-the-holidays/"/>
    <updated>2012-08-28T09:26:45+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/some-monads-after-the-holidays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>After the summer holidays, it&#8217;s time for some Scala and functional programming to bring us back to speed. :-) As such we are re-scheduling, the previous cancelled event on Monads. We&#8217;ll be meeting on the 27th September at 7pm and we will have <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/pub/luc-duponcheel/1/366/6b7">Luc Duponcheel</a> (@LucDup) presenting &#8220;Monads as Computations&#8221;.</p>

<p>This talk deals with the monadic computation interface.
When implemented in Scala it can be used as a DSL for approaching a whole range of computations in a uniform way.
This talk also shows how monads can be transformed to add extra computational features to them (while keeping their original (extra) computational features).</p>

<p>The following extra computational features will be demonstrated:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>state</p></li>
<li><p>control (delimited continuations based)</p></li>
</ul>


<p>In fact, the talk illustrates how to implement a monadic delimited continuations DSL without having to use an extra compiler plugin.
The resulting DSL is only slightly less concise than the one that makes use of the compiler plugin.</p>

<p>If there is some time left then also parallel programming with those monadic delimited continuations can be dealt with.</p>

<p>This BeScala meetup is generously hosted by <strong><a href="http://www.inventivedesigners.com/">Inventive Designers</a></strong> in Antwerpen.</p>

<p>Please <strong><a href="http://bescala.fikket.com/events/monads-as-computations/orders/new">register</a></strong> on the fikket page, as we have to limit participation.</p>

<p><strong>Direction</strong>:
Inventive Designers NV
Sint-Bernardsesteenweg 552
B-2660 Antwerpen</p>

<p><a href="http://www.inventivedesigners.com/">http://www.inventivedesigners.com/
</a> <a href="http://maps.google.be/maps?q=Sint-Bernardsesteenweg+552++B-2660+Antwerpen&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=50.849361,4.735621&amp;sspn=0.012071,0.020084&amp;hnear=Sint-Bernardsesteenweg+552,+Hoboken+2660+Antwerpen,+Vlaams+Gewest&amp;t=m&amp;z=16">GoogleMaps</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Summer Drink]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/summer-drink/"/>
    <updated>2012-06-28T01:29:44+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/summer-drink</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&#8217;s been a long time since our last meet-up.</p>

<p>The holidays are coming and hopefully the sun as well. Therefore we would like organize a drink on the 1st of August.</p>

<p>As usual, we created a Fikket subscription. <a href="http://bescala.fikket.com/event/summer-drink">http://bescala.fikket.com/event/summer-drink</a></p>

<p>Subscription is of course not mandatory, everybody is welcome to join us for a drink.</p>

<p>We&#8217;ll meet at Delirium Café in Brussels at 19 o&#8217;clock.</p>

<p>Address: Impasse de la Fidélité 4 (near central station).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Play! Coding Dojo in Scala, May 21st in Leuven]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/play-coding-dojo-in-scala/"/>
    <updated>2012-04-27T23:40:43+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/play-coding-dojo-in-scala</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2><strong>SOLD OUT! </strong></h2>

<p>During this Dojo we&#8217;ll implement a Play! 2.0 application in Scala.</p>

<p>We&#8217;ll start if a simple CRUD application where we&#8217;ll get in touch with basic usage of forms, page template, database persistence and testing in Play!. If time allows we&#8217;ll go for more advanced features and implement some functionality using Akka.</p>

<p>This BeScala meetup is generously hosted by <strong><a href="http://www.ae.be">AE</a></strong> in Leuven.</p>

<p><strong>What is a coding dojo?</strong></p>

<p>A Coding Dojo is a meeting where a bunch of coders get together to work on a programming challenge. They are there have fun and to engage in Deliberate Practice in order to improve their skills. <a href="http://codingdojo.org/cgi-bin/wiki.pl?WhatIsCodingDojo">http://codingdojo.org/cgi-bin/wiki.pl?WhatIsCodingDojo</a></p>

<p>Please <del><strong><a href="http://bescala.fikket.com/events/play-coding-dojo-in-scala/orders/new">register</a></strong></del> on the fikket page, as we have to limit participation.</p>

<p><strong>Date:</strong>
Monday, May 21st at 19:00.</p>

<p><strong>Where:</strong>
AE
Interleuvenlaan 27B
3001 Heverlee</p>

<p><a href="http://www.ae.be">http://www.ae.be
</a><a href="http://maps.google.be/maps?q=Interleuvenlaan+27B++3001+Heverlee&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=50.805935,4.432983&amp;sspn=6.187081,10.283203&amp;hnear=Interleuvenlaan+27,+3001+Leuven,+Vlaams-Brabant,+Vlaams+Gewest&amp;t=m&amp;z=16">GoogleMaps</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[ScalaCheck Slides from last BeScala Meet-Up]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/scalacheck-slides/"/>
    <updated>2012-02-21T10:43:44+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/scalacheck-slides</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong><a href="http://www.slideshare.net/BeScala/scala-check">ScalaCheck</a></strong></p>

<p>View more <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/thecroaker/death-by-powerpoint">PowerPoint</a> from <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/BeScala">BeScala</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BeScala Meetup at Inventive Designers on Thursday, Feb 16th]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-meetup-2012-02-16/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-30T22:36:30+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-meetup-2012-02-16</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This Scala meetup is generously hosted by Inventive Designers in Antwerp.</p>

<p>7pm meet and greet</p>

<p>7:30pm presentations</p>

<p>The suggested topic for this meetup is &#8220;Scala for testing&#8221;. Even if your team currently only uses Java for development, some of the Scala-based testing libraries (Specs, ScalaTest, ScalaCheck) that we plan to talk about are still an attractive solution, e.g. for BDD and Acceptance Testing, since they provide a strongly typed, IDE-assisted alternative to plain-text-based approaches for behaviour specification.</p>

<p>If you have any experience with Scala for testing, we&#8217;d like to hear about it.</p>

<p>Make sure you subscribe on Fikket if you want to join us.
<a href="http://bescala2012.fikket.com/event/bescala-meetup-at-inventive-designers-on-thursday-feb-16th">http://bescala2012.fikket.com/event/bescala-meetup-at-inventive-designers-on-thursday-feb-16th</a></p>

<p>More info about the location: <a href="http://www.inventivedesigners.com/about/findus">Inventive Designers</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report from the Scala Enthusiasts Gathering Bof @ Devoxx]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/report-from-scala-enthusiasts-gathering/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-15T19:03:47+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/report-from-scala-enthusiasts-gathering</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday, we had the &#8220;Scala Enthusiats Gathering&#8221; BoF at Devoxx. We had between 20 to 30 attendees, some beer and some very interesting discussions about Scala. Most of the attendees were from Europe and Scala experience varied from none to full time Scala developers. We even had a Typesafe employee joining us. :-)</p>

<p>One of the most discussed topic was Scala adoption and how to introduce it at work. As usual the most proposed strategy was to introduce it via non-produciton code, such as testing or support tools (build, deployment, log analysis, etc).</p>

<p>Concerning Scala in production for mixed projects (Java + Scala), one of the proposed approachs was to have Java interfaces implemented in Scala or avoiding Scala methods with functions as parameters if they are to be called from Java.</p>

<p>During the session some of the attendees gave links to their projects on github that could be useful for those willing to learn more about Scala. The list can be found bellow.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/LucDupAtGitHub/GroceryShop">https://github.com/LucDupAtGitHub/GroceryShop</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/LucDupAtGitHub/SimpleDomainStore">https://github.com/LucDupAtGitHub/SimpleDomainStore</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/rcavalcanti/scala-guice">https://github.com/rcavalcanti/scala-guice</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/caelum/hibernate-query-dsl">https://github.com/caelum/hibernate-query-dsl</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/mariofusco/hammurabi">https://github.com/mariofusco/hammurabi</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="https://github.com/OlegIlyenko/scaldi">https://github.com/OlegIlyenko/scaldi</a></p></li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Scala Devoxx Calendar]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/scala-devoxx-calendar/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-03T23:04:11+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/scala-devoxx-calendar</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We have created two Google Calendars with all Devoxx&#8217; <strong>Scala</strong> talks and related topics.</p>

<ul>
<li><p><a href="http://www.google.com/calendar/ical/bescala.org_phtoe0n1i1r2fpg1msnpfvb3do%40group.calendar.google.com/public/basic.ics">Scala @ Devoxx</a></p></li>
<li><p><a href="http://www.google.com/calendar/ical/bescala.org_nfe8pqhn36qtmcne9b5orkj0no%40group.calendar.google.com/public/basic.ics">Other JVM lang</a></p></li>
</ul>


<p>On the later, you&#8217;ll find talks on Groovy, JRuby, Kotlin, Ceylon, Fantom, Java language updates and roadmap, the JavaPosse recording and a talk from Dick Wall about &#8220;Courage in Software Development&#8221;. Considering his involvement with Scala, we can imagine that his talk is of interest to all of us.</p>

<p>You can download the .ics or import the url to you calendar application or Google Calendar.</p>

<p>The calendars are created by hand and may be out-of-sync. Therefore, don&#8217;t forget to check the real one at <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV11/Schedule">Devoxx 2011 Schedule</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BeScala @ Devoxx 2011]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-devoxx-2011/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-26T23:17:02+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-devoxx-2011</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We are pleased to announce that we&#8217;ll be present at <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/">Devoxx 2011</a> with the &#8221;<a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV11/Scala+Enthusiasts+Gathering">Scala Enthusiasts Gathering</a>&#8221; BoF.</p>

<p>Come and join us on Monday 14th at 20:00 for a informal meet-up with other Scala enthusiasts from Belgium and abroad.</p>

<p>The access to the BoFs are <strong>free of charge</strong>, but of course we <strong>strongly</strong> <strong>recommend</strong> a Devoxx subscription.</p>

<p>For those who were living on another planet and don&#8217;t know <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/">Devoxx</a> yet, it is the biggest and best Java conference outside the US (some says it&#8217;s already the best in the world). And it takes place just next door, in Antwerpen.</p>

<p>As usual, Devoxx is featuring a lot of excellent <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/display/DV11/Schedule">talks</a>, some of them on <a href="http://www.devoxx.com/label/DV11/scala">Scala</a>.</p>

<p>Don&#8217;t wait till the last minute, get today your Devoxx <a href="https://reg.devoxx.com/">subscription</a>.</p>

<p><a href="https://reg.devoxx.com/"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/DEVOXX-Banner486x60_V1-anim-300x37.gif" alt="" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Report from last meet-up]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/report-from-last-meet-up/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-19T23:56:31+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/report-from-last-meet-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Last week we had our second meet-up with some very interesting Lightning talks, pizzas and beer! What could a Scala enthusiast ask more? :-)</p>

<p>Some of the presentations are available on slideshare.
<a href="http://www.slideshare.net/BeScala/presentations">http://www.slideshare.net/BeScala/presentations</a></p>

<p>We would like to thanks <a href="http://www.n-side.be/">n-side</a> once again for hosting our meet-up and supporting our group. And for sponsoring the pizzas and drinks. :-)</p>

<p>We have also some fresh news for our small community that we&#8217;ll be announced in the coming days. So, stay tuned&#8230;</p>

<p>And to finalize, a small quote from one of last week speakers. We think that his sentence express a lot our feelings about Scala.</p>

<p><em>&#8220;I used to programme in Python and Ruby. Then, for work, I had to use Java. Now, with Scala, I&#8217;m free again.&#8221;</em>
Cyrille Dejemeppe</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BeScala 2nd Meet-up - Programme]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-2nd-meet-up-programme/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-12T23:21:28+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-2nd-meet-up-programme</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2>Intro</h2>

<p><strong>Louis Jacomet</strong> <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/in/ljacomet"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a> <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/ljacomet"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/twitter.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
BeScala introduction and objectives.</p>

<h2>Lightning talks</h2>

<p><strong>Tim Romberg</strong> <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/pub/tim-romberg/0/862/6a3"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
Short presentation of the Lift web framework, reporting on experience in creating a membership portal</p>

<p><strong>Renato Cavalcanti</strong> <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/in/renatocavalcanti"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a> <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/irenato"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/twitter.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
Scala Guice is a thin layer on top of Google Guice that offers a more Scala like syntax.</p>

<p><strong>Guy Van den Broeck</strong> <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/guyvdb"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
Probabilistic Programming with Scala</p>

<p><strong>Sébastien Doeraene</strong> <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/pub/s%C3%A9bastien-doeraene/36/a3a/348/en"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a> <a href="https://twitter.com/#!/sjrdoeraene"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/twitter.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
Ozma is a conservative extension to Scala with Oz concurrency. Ozma adds dataflow values, lightweight threads, lazy execution and ports to Scala. Dataflow values, which are single-assignment values with automatic synchronization, are a very powerful language primitive for building concurrent software. They allow for declarative concurrency, a model in which concurrency is deterministic and explicit synchronization is not needed. In this talk, we present some of the most powerful programming techniques of Ozma with the help of some examples.</p>

<p><strong>Gilles Scouvart</strong> <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/pub/gilles-scouvart/2/325/152"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a> <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/Gesprye"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/twitter.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
n-Side is using Scala to develop some of its applications. One of the main reasons for that is how easy it makes to create Domain-Specific Languages (DSLs). In our business domain (mathematical optimization), developers are often writing their mathematical models in so-called modelling languages (e.g. AMPL), which typically lack the power of a true general-purpose programming language. On the other hand, general-purpose languages are often not expressive enough for this task. We use the power of Scala to design an internal DSL for optimization: Scampi (Scala Mathematical Programming Interface).</p>

<p><strong>Pierre Schaus</strong> <a href="http://be.linkedin.com/in/pschaus"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
Constraint Programming is an algorithmic approach to solve complex
combinatorial optimization problems.
We&#8217;ll show how to describe and solve problems in Scala using our
state-of-the-art constraint programming solver.
The core implementation of the solver is in Java while the modelling
layer is in Scala.</p>

<p><strong>Bertrand Cornelusse</strong><br/>
Roadeff (french operations research society) is organizing every two
years an optimization competition. We plan to take part this year to
the competition using the various modules of Scampi (n-Side&#8217;s toolkit
to solve optimization problems) all implemented in Scala. We&#8217;ll
shortly describe the problem proposed by Google and the high level
ideas we already found to solve it.</p>

<p><strong>Cyrille Dejemeppe</strong> <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/in/cdejemeppe"><img src="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/images/linkedin.png" alt="" /></a><br/>
N-Side has an optimization tool called CT-Fast which contains a very heavy evaluation process. This program outputs the Pareto set (i.e. the set of optimal points in multiobjective optimization) for some given objectives by using many evaluations of the heavy process mentioned above. I implemented multiobjective optimization algorithms in Scala (I&#8217;ve never used it before) to use less evaluations and thus speed up the execution of the whole tool. The performance obtained are impressive and there is a good hope it can really improve the tool. I have some graphs and animations to show.</p>

<h2>Discussion Panel on Scala Adoption</h2>

<p>With pizzas and drinks. :-)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[BeScala - 2nd meet-up]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-2nd-meet-up/"/>
    <updated>2011-08-25T14:57:48+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala-2nd-meet-up</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Our next meet-up will be held on the 13th September, 19:00 at N-SIDE office.</p>

<p>N-SIDE s.a. - Belgium
Watson &amp; Crick Hill Park - Bldg H
Rue Granbonpré, 11
B- 1348 Louvain-la-Neuve
www.n-side.eu</p>

<p>We&#8217;ll have limited places (maximum 25 people). Therefore, make sure you subscribe on Fikket if you want to join us.
And if for any reason you cannot join, let us know so we can invite people from the wait list.
<a href="http://bescala.fikket.com/event/bescala-2nd-meet-up"> http://bescala.fikket.com/event/bescala-2nd-meet-up</a></p>

<p>For this time we would like to organize Lightning talks. Feel free to come talk about your Scala passion and show/tell us what you have been coding in Scala.
The talks will be 5 minutes in length. See for reference: <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightning_Talk">http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lightning_Talk</a></p>

<p>We also would like to organize a discussion panel about Scala adoption in Belgium. So, if you have ideas, plans/strategies or experience introducing Scala in your company, we are very interested to hear your story. ;-)</p>

<p>And last but not least, a special thanks to the N-SIDE management and in particular to Ciprian Mocanu and Gilles Scouvart for supporting our initiative.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome to BeScala ]]></title>
    <link href="http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-18T18:43:02+02:00</updated>
    <id>http://BeScala.github.com/bescala/bescala</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So, here is our website and its first post!</p>

<p><strong>BeScala</strong>, the<strong> Belgium Scala Enthusiasts</strong> website was born after the first <strong>Belgium Scala Meetup</strong> hold on July 13th, 2011 in Brussels.</p>

<p>Here we&#8217;ll share information about our future meetups, presentations, drinks and all activities related with the Scala programming language in Belgium.</p>

<p>To keep informed about our activity, follow us on: Twitter (<a href="https://twitter.com/#!/be_scala">@be_scala</a>), <a href="http://www.linkedin.com/groups?home=&amp;gid=4001883&amp;trk=anet_ug_hm">LinkedIn</a> and/or <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/bescala">Google Groups</a>.
And of course this website!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
